Change management happens in a cycle.
There is no real stopping point, it is continuously going.
This means that there must be continuous monitoring of that environment.
So if you or anyone should request a change,
it needs to go through the appropriate approvals,
the organization must be prepared for roll back if necessary.
Meaning that if a particular change did not work,
we need to be able to roll back to the legacy system.
While change management is an organization wide process,
it often falls on information security professionals to coordinate
the effort and maybe to provide oversight and governance
depending on the size of the organization.
It may also fall under an it or development area
in organizations that have a quality or risk management department.
It would be a great fit in either of those areas too.
The common theme is that change management acknowledges and incorporates input
from the end users as well as all areas of it,
development, information security and most importantly management
to ensure that all changes are properly tested,
approved and communicated prior to being implemented.